[音乐]
[MUSIC]
&gt；&gt；Kyle Simpson：所以这真的是一种不可反转的控制。
&gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: So it really is an uninversion of control.
现在有更多的承诺。
Now there's more to promises than that.
这确实开始让我更深入地了解如何使用API？
And this does start to get a little bit more into how do I use the API?
这通常是人们开始学习承诺的地方。
This is normally where people start learning promises.
所以我没有忽略教你这部分，但是
So I'm not neglecting teaching you that part, but
你会注意到，我首先为我们建立了一个概念基础。
you'll notice that I built us a foundation of concept first.
现在你明白为什么承诺如此重要了。
Now that you understand why promises are so important.
现在你明白了它们被设计的方式是故意的，
Now you understand that the way that they're designed is intentional,
这是故意的。
it's on purpose.
这是有原因的。
There's a reason for it.
不仅仅是他们不知道如何设计东西。
It's not just that they don't know how to design stuff.
所以，让我们谈谈他们在流量控制方面的做法。
So let's talk about what they do in terms of flow control.
因为在我们的现代JavaScript程序中，很少会出现这种情况，
Because in our modern JavaScript programs, it's very rarely the case,
我们只有一个步骤，如果是异步的话。
that we simply have a single step, if then asynchronously.
有一个行动，然后当它结束时，我们继续前进。
There's one action and then when it's finished we move on.
我们的大多数现代JavaScript程序，大多数正在收听的人，
Most of our modern JavaScript programs, most of you that are listening,
可能正在编写更加复杂的系统。
are probably writing vastly more sophisticated systems.
这两件事必须发生，无论何时结束，我都会继续做下去。
These two things have to happen, and whenever they finish, I move on to this.
然后第三件事在这里爆炸，然后它又回来了。
And then this third thing fires off here, and then it comes back together.
这就是所谓的流量控制。
That's called flow control.
管理所有这些步骤通过程序的方式称为流控制。
Managing how all of those steps go through your program is called flow control.
我们已经看到了流量控制，我们看到了它的隆隆声。
We've seen flow control already, we saw it with thunks.
我们看到了回拨。
We saw it with callbacks.
那么，通过流控制的方式提供的承诺是什么呢？
So what do promises offered by a way of flow control?
他们怎么允许我们这样做，因为一个承诺根本上就是一个如果，
How do they allow us to do, cuz a promise fundamentally is just an if then,
这是一个等待这个完成，然后做下一件事。
it's a wait for this to finish and then do the next thing.
嗯，这对我们没有用，除非有某种方法来作出承诺
Well that's not useful to us unless there's some way to compose promises
一起，我再次使用Word Compose。
together, I used word compose again.
以一种管理我们的流量控制的方式共同撰写承诺。
Compose promises together in a way to to manage our flow control.
所以回到我们友好有趣的伪代码。
So back to our friendly fun pseudocode.
我希望能够做第一件事，然后当它完成后再做第二件事
I'd like to be able to do the first thing, and then when it's finished do the second
事情，当它完成时，做第三件事，当它完成时，完成。
thing, and when it's finished do the third thing, and when it's finished complete.
顺便说一句，如果这条链上有任何错误，
And by the way if there's any error anywhere along that chain,
我想出错。
I'd like to fail out to an error.
这是最基本的顺序流控制。
That's the most basic sense sequential flow control.
承诺如何允许我们管理顺序流控制？
How do promises allow us to manage sequential flow control?
关键特征。
The key characteristic.
这是API设计决策。
It's an API design decision.
连锁承诺。
Chaining promises.
我有一个承诺代表了第一步。
I have one promise that represents the first step.
另一个承诺代表第二步。
Another promise represents the second step.
另一个承诺代表第三步。
Another promise represents the third step.
在这条链上的任何地方，我会向你展示我们是如何把它链在一起的。
And in anywhere along that chain, and I'll show you how we chain on it together.
但在链上的任何地方，如果发生错误，如果
But anywhere along that chain, if an error happens, if
拒绝承诺发生了相反的情况，我们失败在拒绝链中。
a rejection of the promise happens rather, we fail out to the rejection chain.
好吗？
Okay?
所以连锁承诺，
So chaining promises,
这是你的钥匙带走，以了解连锁承诺是如何发生的。
here's your key take away to understand how chaining promises happen.
你把诺言A和诺言B连在一起的方式，
The way you take a promise A and chain it with a promise B,
是不是在承诺A中，当您为承诺A设置事件处理程序时。
is that in the promise A, when you set up event handler for a promise A.
在该处理程序中，您返回承诺B。
In that handler you return promise B.
你还一个承诺，
You return one promise,
您从第一个承诺的成功处理程序返回第二个承诺。
you return the second promise from the success handler of the first promise.
然后神奇地把他们锁在一起。
And magically they chained together.
它实际上并不是那么神奇，它实际上是当你实现承诺的时候
It's actually not so magical, it's actually when you implement promise
图书馆，你会发现这实际上很复杂。
libraries, you find out it's actually pretty complicated to do.
但尽管如此，它还是被设计成这样，我们会为你处理这项工作。
But nonetheless it's been designed to do that, we take care of that work for you.
所以你需要做的就是制作一系列的链条，
So that all you need to do to make a series of chains,
是从前一个成功处理程序返回一个承诺。
is to return one promise from the success handler of the previous one.
所以做的第一件事就是给我们一个承诺。
So do first thing is gonna give us a promise.
我们建立了一个当时的处理人，我们可以做任何我们需要做的事情。
We set up a then handler, we do whatever we need to do with that.
然后我们调用dosecondThing。
And then we call doSecondThing.
DosecondThing做出了另一个承诺，你会注意到我们做了，就是我们退货。
DoSecondThing makes another promise, and you'll notice that we do, is we return it.
通过返回它，它意味着第五行上的.Then处理程序，这
And by returning it, it means that the .then handler on line five, which
通常会在第二行的处理程序之后立即进行。
would normally have proceeded immediately after the handler from line two.
它不再会立即进行。
It no longer is going to proceed immediately.
相反，第五行的.Then处理程序将等待
Instead the .then handler from line five is going to wait for
承诺再次出现在三号线上。
the promise returned on line three.
它会把这些东西连在一起。
It's going to chain those things together.
它在封面下将其交换出去，并为您处理所有的复杂性。
It swaps it out underneath the covers and handles all that complexity for you.
因此，我们可以通过将承诺链接在一起来近似流控制。
So we can approximate a flow control by chaining our promises together.
现在，这本可以用thunks和
Now, this could have been done with thunks and
这可能是通过回调完成的。
it could have been done with callbacks.
我们已经做过了。
We've done this already.
已经有一组连续的步骤了，你知道这看起来像什么。
A sequential set of steps already, you know what that looks like.
而且它经常会在一系列嵌套的回调中对自己进行模式。
And it often does pattern itself in a nested series of callbacks.
所以人们对承诺感到兴奋的一件事就是当他们
So one of the big things that people get excited about with promises when they
参见示例承诺代码，
see example promise code,
他们对它不再嵌套的想法感到兴奋。
they get excited about this idea that it's not nested anymore.
它被组织成一条垂直链。
It's organized into a vertical chain.
这是承诺中最不重要的部分。
That is the least important part of promises.
不是无关紧要。
Not unimportant.
这是最不重要的部分。
It's the least important part.
事实上我会对你说实话
In fact I'll be honest with you,
当我第一次开始写承诺的时候，这就是我所做的一切。
when I first started writing promises this is all I did.
我用承诺的链重写了我所有的异步代码，
I rewrote all of my asynchronous code using promised chains,
我完全沉醉于这样一个想法：这是编写代码的正确方式。
I became completely drunk on the idea that that's the right way to write my code.
几年后回想起来，我并不真的使用承诺链
And upon reflection a couple of years later, I don't really use promise chains
再也没有了，这是最不重要的部分，我可以接受，也可以不管。
anymore, it's the least important part, I could take it or leave it.
因为事实证明有更好的方法来进行流量控制，而且
Because it turns out there's better ways of doing flow control, and
我们晚点再谈这个。
we're gonna get to that a little bit later.
有比允诺链更好的方法来实现我们的流控制。
There's better ways of doing our flow control than a promise chain.
承诺链比thunk嵌套系列更好吗？
Is a promise chain better than a thunk nested series?
是啊。
Yep.
它比我们称之为回调的东西好吗？
Is it better than whatever the crap we call the callback stuff
我们之前写的？
that we wrote before?
绝对的。
Absolutely.
好多了。
It's better.
但这不是最重要的部分。
But this isn't the important part.
所以，给我不变性，安全和信任，我就可以离开了。
So, give me the immutability and the safety and the trust, and I could leave.
我可以接受或离开流量控制，承诺的链条。
I could take or leave the flow control, the chaining of promises.
现在，如果我不教你它们是如何工作的，那我就是失职了。
Now, I'd be remiss if I didn't teach you how they work.
所以我们要花一点时间来理解承诺的链接。
So we are gonna spend a little bit of time understanding promised chaining.
但我只想让你知道它在整个范围内的位置
But I just want you to know where it sits within the whole scope and
我们正在谈论的计划。
scheme of what we're talking about.
你需要理解它
You're gonna need to understand it,
因为你要写很多框架代码。
cuz you're gonna write a lot of framework code.
有很多角度和反应，
There's a lot of angulars and reacts,
以及所有将使用承诺链的人。
and all that are out there that are gonna use promise chains.
但我想让你记住在你的脑海里。
But I want you to remember in the back of your head.
为什么使用这些承诺是如此重要。
Why using those promises is so important.
它真的与链条无关。
It really has nothing to do with the chaining stuff.
好吗？
Okay?
这是另一个例子，这个例子使用延迟。
Here's another example, this one is using delay.
所以我们实际上是根据时间延迟的，你可以用它来
So we're actually delaying based upon times, and you could use that for
例如，动画链。
an animation chain for example.
人们已经写了延迟的动画，当然，
People have written animations with delays, and of course,
工作方式完全相同。
works exactly the same way.
&GT；&GT；凯尔·辛普森：回到整个计算生命意义的事情。
&gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: Back to that whole calculating the meaning of life thing.
这里是生命的意义表现为一个许诺的链条。
Here is the meaning of life represented as a promise chain.
GetData(10)返回承诺
GetData(10) returns a promise
从现在开始的1000毫秒将解决承诺。
that 1000 milliseconds from now will resolve the promise.
你会注意到承诺不仅仅是关于if then，而是
And you'll notice that promises are not just about an if then, but
它们也是关于消息传递的。
they are about message passing as well.
因此当getData(10)完成时，
So when getData(10) finishes,
它将数据传递到承诺链中的下一步。
it passes that data along to the next step in the promise chain.
我们把它放在1号。
And we get it in num1.
然后当getData(30)从现在开始结束1000毫秒时，
And then when getData(30) finishes a 1000 milliseconds from now,
使用值30调用num2。
num2 is called with the value 30.
然后，当这个承诺解决时，答案就是这个值。
And then when that promise resolves, the answer is given that value.
因此允诺链确实从一步到一步向下传播数据，
So the promise chain does propagate data down from step to step to step,
这是一个非常重要的强大的东西。
which is a really important powerful thing.
承诺不仅表示流控制，而且
Promises not only represent flow control, but
它们也代表通过我们步骤的数据流。
they are also represent data flow through our steps.